Partial Guide to the I. Edward Kiev Papers, circa 1860 - circa 1980 K0001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets, circa 1860-circa 1970; K0001 Series 4; 18 linear feet (Box 14, Box 11, Box 16, Box 15, Box 10, Box 51, Box 9, Box 8, Box 7, Box 18, Box 45, Box 46, Box 49, Box 2, Box 1, Box 53, Box 52, Box 48, Box 6, Box 17, Box 5, Box 4, Box 3)
  - Der zionistische Student: Flugschrift des K.Z.V (Kartell Zionistischer Verbindungen), 1913 (Box 16, Folder 1202)
  - Juden und Christen: Autorisirte Uebersetzung mit einleitendem Vorwort von Dr. Adolf Blummenthal, 1888 (Box 16, Folder 1203)
    Translation of: Juifs et chrtiens
  - Juden im Trkischen Orient, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 1204)
    "In hundert Exemplaren als Hs. gedruckt."
  - Damaskus, ein Wort zur Abwehr; nebst einem Verzeichniss der Schriften des Verfassers mit Anmerkungen, in zweiter Ausgabe, 1859 (Box 16, Folder 1205)
  - Abwehr-Bltter: Mitteilungen aus dem Verein zur Abwehr des Antisemitismus, 10/1931 (Box 16, Folder 1206)
    Very brittle
  - Abwehr-Bltter: Mitteilungen aus dem Verein zur Abwehr des Antisemitismus, 04/1932 (Box 16, Folder 1207)
  - Diskussionsschriften ber die Judenfrage: das neue Gesicht des Antisemitismus, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 1208)
    "Sonderabdruck aus den 'B'nai B'rith' Mitteilungen fr Osterreich"
  - Die Aufgaben der Juden im Weltkriege, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 1209)
  - Die Errichtung der jdischen nationalen Heimsttte in Palstina = The Establishment in Palestine of the Jewish national home: Denkschrift berreicht von der Zionistischen Organisation an den Generalsekretr des Vlkerbundes zur Informierung der Stndigen Mandatskommission, Oktober 1924 (Box 16, Folder 1210)
    Texzt in German and English
  - Aufbau und Umbau: zum Problem des jdischen Wirtschaftslebens in Osteuropa, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 1211)
    Sonderdruck aus "Der Morgen"; Heft 4
  - Schriften zur Geschichte der Juden: eine Bibliographie der in Deutschland und der Schweiz 1922-1955 erschienenen Dissertationen, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 1212)
    Schriftenreihe wissenschaftliche Abhandlungen des Leo Baeck Institute of Jews from Germany, 4
  - Jdische Alterthmer in Worms und Speier, 1896 (Box 16, Folder 1213)
  - Festpredigt zum 50 jhrigen Jubilum der Synagoge in Mnchen, gehalten in der Synagoge zu Mnchen am 5. September 1937, Erew Rosch-Haschonoh 5698 (Box 16, Folder 1214)
  - Beitrge zur Sozial- und Wirtschaftsgeschichte der Berliner Juden vor der Emanzipation, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 1215)
  - Zur Geschichte der Juden in Magdeburg: Grstentheils nach Urkunden des Magdeburger Kgl. Provinzial-Archivs, 1866 (Box 16, Folder 1216)
  - Eine jdische Hochschule, 1902 (Box 16, Folder 1217)
  - Die Mischehe im Judentum im Lichte der Geschichte, 1905 (Box 16, Folder 1218)
  - Berhmte jdische Frauen in Vergangenheit und Gegenwart, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 1219)
    Das Licht, Heft 13
  - Deutsch-Amerikanische Skizzen fr jdische Auswanderer und Nichtauswanderer, 1857 (Box 16, Folder 1220)
    Schriften herausgegeben vom Institute zur Frderung der israelitischen Literatur, Zweites Jahr: 1856/57
  - Der Mensch als Spiegelbild der Natur betrachtet: Kanzel-Vortrag am Sabbat Nachamu (31. Juli) im israelitischen Tempel zu Carlsbad gehalten, 1852 (Box 16, Folder 1221)
  - Die Amsterdamer Hagada: 18 Abbildungen aus dem Kupferstichdruckeder Passah-Hagada, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 1222)
    Jdische Bcherei, Bd. 5
  - Ha-im golat Amerikah hi Bavel?, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 1223)
    Title on verso page: "Is American Jewry a second Babel?"
  - ha-Ason veha-immut, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 1224)
  - Tazkir ha-Sokhnut ha-Yehudit le-erets-Yisrael le-vaadat ha-hekirah ha-Anglo-Amerikait, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 1225)
    Anglo-American Committee of Inquiry on Jewish Problems in Palestine and Europe
  - ha-Protokolim shel mifkadat ha-Irgun Tseva ha-Leumi (Yuli-November 1944), 1975 (Box 16, Folder 1226)
    In Hebrew, but contains an English cover, which reads: Shlomo Lev-Ami, The Minutes of the Irgun Zvai Leumi (I.Z.L) July-November 1944. Reprint from: Zionism, Vol. IV, Tel Aviv University, Hakibbutz Hameuchad Publishing House 1975
  - Hatsat matsaha-miflagah le-bihirot le-keneset ha-shlishit, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 1227)
  - Yehuda Benari (1904-1984), 1986 (Box 16, Folder 1228)
  - Demografiyah, demokratiyah, ve-Otonomyah, 03/1988 (Box 16, Folder 1229)
  - Sipuah Akhshav!, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 1230)
  - Tarbut, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 1231)
  - Zeev Zabotinski, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 1232)
    Ishim ba-am ha-Yehudi
  - Pinhas Dashevski: perek mi-gevurat Yisrael ba-golah, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 1233)
  - ha-Gedud ha-shishi mesaper, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 1234)
    Sifriyat kis la-hayal ha-Ivri; v 9
  - Hirhurim: al haye olam ve-haye shaah, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 1235)
  - Roma vi-Yerushalayim, 1900 - 1975 (Box 16, Folder 1236)
  - Sefer Ahikar he-hakham, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 1237)
    Includes bibliographical references (p. 19-20)
  - Shirim min ha-epos ha-Serbi, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 1238)
    Sifriyah ketanah shel hotsaat Shoken, 1
  - Sefer Toldot ha-yamim: she-avru al Hevra kadisha "Shivah- keruim" ve-al Bet ha-midrash ha-gadol asher ba-ir Minsk mi-shenat 5523 ad shenat 5664 ...hov. 1 (1904) (Box 16, Folder 1239)
    Shivah keruim (Minsk, Belarus)
  - Sefer ha-pitgamim: sheloshah sefarim bo niftahim; Pitgame ha-melekh Shelomoh u-musaro ... "Pitgame Yehoshe Ben-Sira u-musaro: be-tseruf pitgame ha-sefer hokmat Shelomoh, 1930 - 1931 (Box 16, Folder 1240)
  - Sefer Tefilat ha-derekh: ve-nilveh elav ezo perakim be-divre musar ha-shayakhim leha-nosim bi-mesilat ha-barzel ve-asher yikaru be-shem Orhot hayim, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 1241)
  - Kinot le-Tishah be-Av, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 1242)
  - Deot (Jerusalem) "Bittaon ha-akademaim ha-datiyim": Win. 1971 no. 40 (Box 16, Folder 1243)
  - Piyute Yanai li-shema Yi'srael: kerobah le-seder debarim 6:4, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 1244)
  - Le-toldot ha-sugiya, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 1245)
  - Bibliografyah musikalit vrit, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 1246)
  - Zemirot Yisrel: kolel seder tikune Shabat u-zemirot ... im perush Iyun Tefilah le-harav Yakov Zevi Meklenburg ... u-firush Derekh Hayyim le-r[av] Yakov Mi-Lisa, 1956 - 1956 (Box 16, Folder 1247)
  - Be-keren-zavit: shirei-mishak le-ganei-yeladim u-le-vatei-sefer: helek 2, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 1248)
    Melodies for voice and piano, vocalized Hebrew words. Hebrew words also printed as text before each song.
  - Shevile ha-hinukh: Vol. 34, no. 1, Autumn 1973 (Box 16, Folder 1249)
    Editors: 1925-27, Nisson Touroff. - 1927-29, S.B. Maximon. - Oct. 1930, P. Churgin, S. Rosenfeld, L.I. Riklis. - Jan./Feb. 1940- Zevi Scharfstein
  - Shevile ha-hinukh Shanah 1: Sedrah 2: hov. 1, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 1250)
  - Manit: Bitn nor ha-moshavim: Sedrah: 2 [68] Feb. 1969, 2/1969 (Box 16, Folder 1251)
    Supersedes a publication with the same title, published 1944-
  - Manit: Bittn nor ha-moshavim, sedrah 2 [hov. 93] Sept. 1974, 09/1974 (Box 16, Folder 1252)
  - Reshimat Sefarim: 1961 (Box 16, Folder 1253)
  - Kuntres ha-konamot: be-nyane hilkhot konam v?e-hek?desh ve-sure hanah, 1900 - 1975 (Box 16, Folder 1270)
    Title on verso page: Talmudic-rabbinical treatise
  - ha-Mor = Hamaor: Rabbinical Monthly Journal, vol. 12, no. 4, 04/1962 (Box 16, Folder 1271)
  - Simhah l pi derekh ha-hasidut, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 1272)
  - Mamre Hasidut: ...mi-Admor...mi-Lubavitsh, 1930 - 1931 (Box 16, Folder 1273)
    Kuntres; 10
  - Military and archaeological aspects of the conquest of Canaan in the Book of Joshua, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 1274)
    Published in cooperation with the Department for Education and Culture in the Diaspora of the Jewish Agency
  - The nature of the prophet (with special emphasis on Jeremiah), 1965 (Box 16, Folder 1275)
    El hayin; no. 12
  - Sipure ha-Mikra li-yeladim (m tsiyurim): vol. 1, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 1276)
  - Sipure ha-Mikra li-yeladim (m tsiyurim): vol. 3, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 1277)
  - Sipure ha-Mikra li-yeladim (m tsiyurim): vol. 4, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 1278)
  - Bamah: hov. 8, 03/1961 (Box 16, Folder 1279)
  - Bamah: hov. 31, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 1280)
  - Bamah: hov. 52, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 1281)
  - Bamah: hov. 59, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 1282)
  - l amanit Amanim u-mebakrehem: Barukh Shats: Pitgamin u-mikktamim, 1924 - 1925 (Box 17, Folder 1283)
    Inscribed by author on verso of title page and on page 1, number 62 of printing
  - Nefesh-ha-Adam ve-Hayah-haDat: Shelosh hartsaot, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 1284)
  - Jerusalem: A Geopolitical Imperative, 05/1975 (Box 17, Folder 1293)
    reprinted from Midstream, a monthly Jewish Review
  - Jerusalem: Holy City of Three Religions, 01/1977 (Box 17, Folder 1294)
  - Roots in Zion, 09/1976 (Box 17, Folder 1295)
  - The Constitutional and Legal System of Israel, 10/1957 (Box 17, Folder 1296)
  - Maser, the precepts of tithing, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 1297)
  - One People: an address by Simon Greenberg, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 1298)
  - Judaism in the World - Today and Tomorrow: An address, 11/17/1963 (Box 17, Folder 1299)
  - Conservative Judaism: an address, 11/17/1963 (Box 17, Folder 1300)
  - Basis of Unity: an address, 11/17/1963 (Box 17, Folder 1301)
  - Resolutions, 11/17/1963 (Box 17, Folder 1302)
  - Inaugural Address to the Golden Jubilee Convention, 11/17/1963 (Box 17, Folder 1303)
  - Hagadah ve-Seder shel Pesah = form of service for the two first nights of the feast of Passover: with English translation, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 1304)
  - Hagadah shel Pesah = Passover Haggadah, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 1305)
    English rendering by Abraham Regelson, illustrated by Siegmund Forst
  - The children's Haggadah for Passover, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 1306)
    In English with vocalized Hebrew
  - Hagadah fr Pessach, frei bearbeitet, 1900 - 1938 (Box 17, Folder 1307)
    In German
  - Mahadurah meyuhedet shel ha-Sherut ha-dati, Tseva Haganah Le-Yisrel, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 1308)
  - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 1309)
    Attached to standing bookboard (16 x 11 cm.) decorated to look like wood with gilt Egyptian figures and Hebrew wording: "Birkhot le-h?ag ha-H?erut."
  - Gakomo Mirber (1791-1864): tarukhah murgenet be-zrat ha-Sifriyah ha-lumit be-Pariz=Giacomo Meyerbeer (1791-1864): exposition organis'ee avec le concours de la Biblioth`eque nationale de Paris, 12/1964 (Box 17, Folder 1310)
    Hebrew and French
  - Sacred minstrelsey: b a lecture on Biblical and post-Biblical Hebrew music, illustrated by several pieces, either for the piano, or organ, 1863 (Box 17, Folder 1311)
    Chiefly in English with some vocalized Hebrew. First published: London: Bosworth and Harrison, 1860.
  - Bibliography of the publications of Eric Werner, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1312)
  - Moses Soyer, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 1313)
  - The Jewish songster, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 1314)
    Song texts in English, Hebrew (in Hebrew and romanized characters), and Yiddish (romanized) without music. The music was also available in blue print form through the Music Department of the New York Board of Education.
  - Selected writings and lectures of Joseph Yasser: an annotated bibliography, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 1315)
  - Builders of Zion (Bonay Zion): Hebrew cantata based on Palestinian songs, for solo voices, unison or two part chorus and piano, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 1316)
    Title also in Hebrew. Published under the auspices of Temple Beth El, Providence, R.I. Performing time 18 minutes
  - Sabbath eve sacred service: for cantor, mixed voices, and organ accompaniment, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 1317)
    Sacred Music Press [of the] Hebrew Union College, Jewish Institute of Religion
  - The Bible in song: the stories of the Pentateuch in rhyme and song.; vol. 1, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 1318)
    Stories of the Pentateuch in rhyme and song. For children's voices with piano accompaniment.
  - Horah ve-hodayah = Praise and dance; choral ballet, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 1319)
    For chorus (SATB) and piano; Hebrew (transliterated) and English words. Duration: about 30 min.
  - Man's right to life, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 1320)
    Issues of conscience
  - Moses: an address, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 1321)
    A lecture first delivered by Henry George in San Francisco in June, 1878. It was repeated in Dundee on 3rd February, 1884; in Glasgow on 28th December, 1884; and many other places, in New York on 27th November, 1887. The present text is that of the Address delivered in Glasgow.
  - Dynamic Thinking in Wartime, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 1322)
  - Stephen S. Wise, people's champion, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 1323)
  - By-laws of the B'nai Berith Benevolent Society: adopted at the special meeting, April 10th, 1862, 1875 (Box 17, Folder 1324)
    Neben-Gesetze der B'nai Berith Benevolent Society. English and German on parallel pages.
  - A Hebrew primer: intended as an introduction to the spelling and reading of Hebrew with the points compiled for the use of children and beginners, 1851 (Box 17, Folder 1325)
  - When you speak English you're often talking Hebrew, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 1326)
  - New pocket guide to Israeli Hebrew, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1327)
    Presented by The General Israel Orphans Home for Girls
  - Hebrew book review; no. 6 Fall 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1328)
  - State Jewish Museum in Prague = le Musee national juif de Prague, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1329)
    English and French
  - The Hebrew book: an essay, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 1330)
  - A jubilee of the spirit: Address on the occasion of the 50th anniversary of the founding of the Jewish Institute of Religion, May 31, 1972, 5/1972 (Box 17, Folder 1331)
  - Case against the "unification plan" regarding the Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 1332)
  - Why the Bible should not be read in the public schools, 1906 (Box 17, Folder 1333)
  - The sectarian invasion of our public schools ...: and Resolutions and opinions opposing the Miller bill, no. 128 in the California Assembly and similar legislation throughout the United States, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 1334)
  - American Jews: their story, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 1335)
    The One nation library
  - Notes relating to the celebration of the two hundred and fiftieth anniversary of the settlement of the Jews in the United States, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 1336)
    Executive Committee on the Celebration of the 250th Anniversary of the Settlement of the Jews in the United States
  - Judaism's influence in the founding of the republic, 1930 - 1939 (Box 17, Folder 1337)
    Jewish tracts; no. 8
  - The Sephardim of the United States: an exploratory study., 1974 (Box 17, Folder 1338)
    Reprinted with slight modification from The American Jewish Yearbook, 1973
  - The larger task: address delivered at the ninetieth ordination exercises of the Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, Cincinnati, Ohio, June, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 1339)
  - Action for unity, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 1340)
    Jewish affairs: v.2: no. 4, Jan.15, 1948
  - An introduction to the history of Labour Settlement in Palestine, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 1341)
    Zionist library, no. 3: Translation of Bereshit (romanized form)
  - Speeches of British statesmen on Judaism and Zionism, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 1342)
    Jdische Lesehefte, Nr. 14
  - Tempo of Palestine: four years Jewish mass immigration, 1932-1936 (Box 17, Folder 1343)
    Labor Palestine pamphlets
  - Report of the Secretary and Special Delegate of the Joint Foreign Committee on questions of Jewish interest at the fourth assembly of the League, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 1344)
    presented to the Board of Deputies of British Jews and the Council of the Anglo-Jewish Association, November, 1923
  - The yishuv in Palestine--structure and organization, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 1345)
  - On culture contact and its working in modern Palestine, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 1346)
    Memoir series of the American Anthropological Association, no. 67. American anthropologist. New ser., v. 49, no. 4, pt. 2, October, 1947
  - Tribute to the Honorable Julius Rosenwald and Mrs. Rosenwald: Speeches and proceedings at the reception to the Honorable Julius Rosenwald at Hotel St. Regis, New York City, April 14, 1918, 4/14/1918 (Box 17, Folder 1347)
  - The court Jew Lippold: Tale of a sixteenth century martyrdom, 1893 (Box 17, Folder 1348)
    Lippold, mintmaster of Joachim II, elector of Brandenburg, d. 1573
  - Lion of Judah: Judah Leon Magnes, 1877-1948, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 1349)
    "An address at a 'Memorial Hour' in tribute to Dr. Judah Leon Magnes, held under the auspices of The American Friends of the Hebrew University at University House, New York City, November 6, 1958, to mark the tenth anniversary of the death of Hebrew University's first Chancellor and President."
  - The Jews of Coro, Venezuela, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 1350)
    Monographs of the American Jewish Archives, no. 8
  - Czechoslovakia and the Czechoslovak Jews: addresses delivered at the meeting of the Czechoslovak Jewish Representative Committee ... November 18, 1944, at the Community Center, New York, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 1351)
    Addresses by: Frederick Fried, Jan Papanek, Stephen S. Wise, S. Sydney Silverman, and Ernest Frischer
  - Jewish education in a secular society: A symposium on public aid to non-public education, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 1352)
    based on proceedings of the Conference on Public Aid to Non-public Education
  - The Jewish minority in Roumania; correspondence with the Roumanian government respecting the grievances of the Jews, presented to the Board of Deputies of British Jews and the Council of the Anglo-Jewish Association, June, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 1353)
  - Jews and Judaism in the United States: a syllabus, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 1354)
  - Father Coughlin: his "facts" and arguments, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 1355)
  - Conference on anti-semitism, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1356)
    Papers delivered at the fourth Lerntag of the American Federation of Jews from Central Europe, inc., New York City, March 23, 1969
  - Jewish achievements in Palestine, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 1357)
    Palestine papers, no. 6
  - America and the holy land: a colloquium: convened in New York City on the occasion of the tenth anniversary of the Institute of Contemporary Jewry, the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, under the auspices of its International Committee, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 1358)
    Session I. America and the Holy Land as a field of scholarly inquiry -- Session II. United States policy on Palestine in the FDR era -- Session III. Exploration: ideas and themes -- Session IV. Archival sources in the United States and Israel
  - Proceedings of the Zionist Congress held at Basle, Switzerland, August 29, 30 and 31, 1897 (Box 17, Folder 1359)
  - Report on the state of Palestine submitted to His Excellency the High Commissioner for Palestine by the Executive Committee, Palestine Arab Congress on the 13th of October, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 1360)
  - Cultural relations between Jews and Arabs in the middle ages, undated (Box 17, Folder 1361)
  - The closing speech of Sir Boyd Merriman K.C.M.B: delivered on behalf of the Jewish Agency before the Shaw Inquiry Commission in Jerusalem on December 24, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 1362)
    Library's copy missing last 2 pages
  - Why I am a non-Zionist, 1942; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 1363)
  - A call to the educated Jew, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 1364)
    Reprint of an address first delivered in 1914
  - The progress of Zionism, 1899 (Box 17, Folder 1365)
    Publications of the American Federation of Zionists, no. 2
  - Yosef Pamoni - 5652-5726 (1902-1966), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1366)
  - The parting of the ways: essays on the philosophy of Zionism, 1905 (Box 17, Folder 1367)
    translated from the original Hebrew of Achad-Haam by Lilian Ruth Bentwich
  - Analysis of Zionism, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 1368)
    Avukah translations, no. 2
  - American Israel review: v.1: no.6 (Apr./May1957), 4/1957 (Box 17, Folder 1369)
    Vol. 1, no. 1 preceded by a preliminary issue, dated Mar. 1957, called New outlook
  - To choose or not to choose, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 1370)
  - Zionism & Jewish religion, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 1371)
  - Confession, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 1372)
    translation of "Gottes Volk": Jewish pocket books; no. 1
  - Palestine. b Statement of policy by His Majesty's government in the United Kingdom. Presented by the secretary of state for the colonies to Parliament by command of His Majesty, October, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 1373)
  - Our heritage and the world today: a symposium, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 1374)
    The Jew in the world today / by A.L. Sachar -- Reinterpreting our heritage / by L.W. Schwarz
  - Like all the nations?, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 1375)
  - An epistle to the Hebrews, 1900 (Box 17, Folder 1376)
    Publications of the Federation of American Zionists; no. 6
  - The future of human community, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1377)
  - Jewish poverty issues, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 1378)
    Reprinted from various sources
  - Jewish cause cele`bre in sixteenth century Italy (the Pesakim of 1519), 1932 (Box 17, Folder 1379)
    Reprinted from: Abhandlungen zur Erinnerung an Hirsch Perez Chajes. Vienna: Alexander Kohut Memorial Foundation, 1932?
  - Politics and theology in Talmudic Babylonia, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1380)
    B.G. Rudolph lectures in Judaic studies. Lecture delivered on May 15, 1969, at Syracuse University
  - Ancient synagogue of Sardis, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 1381)
    Archaeological Exploration of Sardis, (1958- )
  - Israel: no. 7 [English edition], 1966 (Box 17, Folder 1382)
    Published by the Ministry for Foreign Affairs, Dept. of Information
  - Journal of the Society of Oriental Research: v.15: no.3/4 (Jul.Nov.1931), 7/1931 (Box 17, Folder 1383)
  - Hillel journal: Vol. 1 (1960) (Box 17, Folder 1384)
  - A Christian looks at the Jewish problem [Carl Hermann Voss]: A Jew looks at the Christian problem: Philip S. Bernstein: two addresses, with a foreward by John Haynes Holmes, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 1385)
  - American Jew: Transcript of a panel discussion among Emanuel M. Honig, Allan Beigel, Sydney M. Kanev, Barry M. Glassman, Maxwell N. Wiesman, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 1386)
    Cultural issues in contemporary psychiatry
  - Among my books, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 1387)
    Zionistic interludes and M. Nahum Sokolow -- Jewish credentials and the late Joseph Jacobs -- John Reuchlin and the Hebrew books -- The Jewish state and Theodor Herzl
  - Halachah and Aggadah, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 1388)
    Originally appeared in The New Judea. Translation of ha-Halakhah veha-agadah.
  - Origin and nature of the Geonic works Methiboth and Sepher Hefez, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 1389)
  - Philosophy of purpose, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 1390)
    Studies in Torah Judaism, v 1
  - "The religion of Dr. Grant", 1923 (Box 17, Folder 1391)
    A discussion from a Jewish point of view discourse delivered by Nathan Krass, Sunday, February 4, 1923, at Central Synagogue, New York; being a verbatim stenographic report
  - Hospital compendium: a guide to Jewish moral and religious principles in hospital practice, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 1392)
  - Why no science in Judaism?, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 1393)
  - Interrelations of Judaism, science, philosophy and ethics; Judaism, the Jew and The State of Israel: two series of lectures by Leo Baeck, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 1394)
    Lectures delivered in Dec. 1949 and March 1950 at the Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion
  - Shulhan aruk as a guide for religious practice today, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 1395)
  - On Jewish learning, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 1396)
    "Opening day address, 1962"
  - Religious experience in Judaism, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 1397)
    delivered at the International Conference, World Union for Progressive Judaism, Amsterdam, Holland, July 7th, 1957.
  - So-called "suffering servant" in Isaiah 53, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 1398)
    The Goldenson lecture: Lecture delivered April 22, 1964
  - Social relevance of the eighth-century prophets, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 1399)
    The Goldenson lecture, 1973